John Canaday Papers
John Canaday Papers
1954-1966
Canaday, John,1907-
12.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, New York Times art critic. Correspondence, biographical materials, manuscript reviews and articles.
148885
Biographical History
John Canaday (1907-) was an American writer and art critic for the New York Times.
Born in Fort Scott, Kansas, on Feb. 1, 1907, Canaday received his B.A. from the University of Texas in 1929 and his M.A. from Yale in 1933. From 1938 to 1950, Mr. Canaday taught art history in the department of architecture at the University of Virginia. From 1950-1952, he served as director of the Newcomb School of Art at Tulane University. In 1953, he became Chief of the Division of Education of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, a position which he held until 1959. Beginning in 1959, Canaday served as art critic for the New York Times. He wrote a series, "Metropolitan Seminars in Art," as well as Mainstreams of Modern Art, Embattled Critic, and articles for various magazines. He also published seven mystery novels under the pseudonym "Matthew Head."
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John Canaday Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, and manuscripts. Correspondence, which includes both incoming and outgoing, is almost entirely related to Canaday's articles; the small amount which does not is at the end of the series. Manuscripts are of articles, all untitled, and book reviews.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, is arranged chronologically according to the date of publication of the article to which it relates. Correspondence unrelated to any specific article is arranged alphabetically by subject. Manuscripts are subdivided by type (articles and reviews).
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Canaday, John, 1907- -- Archives.; Head, Matthew, 1907-; Art criticism.; Art critics -- United States.; Authors, American.; Novelists, American.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Art critics.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Canaday, 1966-1969.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - "Happy New Year!", Sept. 6, 1959; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - "Happy New Year!", Sept. 6, 1959; re letters of comment, published 9/20/59 (Box 1)
  - "A Manet Sextet", Sept. 13, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "American Prints", Sept. 20, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "New Directions in Architecture", Sept. 22, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "A Blue Note", Sept. 27, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Feeling Better", Oct. 4, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "The Delights of Drawing", Oct. 18, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Wright vs. Painting", Oct. 21, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Rodman, Selden, Nov. 1, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Welcome Home", Nov. 1, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Cezanne's Way", Nov. 8, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Dubuffet and Picasso", Nov. 15, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Whitney and Modern Museums Show Wares", Nov. 18, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "An Unfinished Art Story", Nov. 21, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Art and Display"', Nov. 22, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Plain but Honest", Nov. 29, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Before Columbus", Dec. 6, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Courbet's World", Dec. 20, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Art Disinherited", Dec. 29, 1959 (Box 1)
  - "Two American Painters", Jan. 3, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Survey with a Hopeful Ear to the Ground", Jan. 10, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Tenth Street", Jan. 17 1960 (Box 1)
  - "A Contemporary Landscape", Jan. 20, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Evolution of a Public", Jan. 31, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Sculptured Pictured", Feb. 9, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Cross-Purposes", Feb. 14, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Secondarily Art", Feb. 21, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "A Quiet Market", Feb. 28, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "It Talks Good!", Mar. 6, 1960 (Box 1)
  - (Magazine section) "Monet's Eye and the Camel's Eye", Mar. 6, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "A World of Light", Mar. 13, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Odd Kind of Art", Mar. 27, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Word of Mouth", Apr. 3, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Degas and People", Apr. 10, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "Sir Herbert Read: In Defense of Abstract Art", Apr. 17, 1960 (Box 1)
  - "On Innocence", May 1, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Children, Amateurs, and Artists", May 8, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "An Italian Sculptor", May 10, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "An American Survey Tour", May 15, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "New York, U.S.A.", May 22, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Dali for a Dollar", May 29, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Perfect Company", June 5, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Promising Mutations", July 24, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Easy Does It", July 31, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "People at a Museum", Aug. 7, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Museum Treat", Aug. 14, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Fifth Avenue and 42nd", Aug. 21, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Of the Peaceable Kingdom", Aug. 28, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Perhaps Drastic", Sept. 4, 1960 (Box 2)
  - (Magazine section) "Lesson for the Clinic-Museums", Sept. 4, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "In the Gloaming", Sept. 11, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "A Broader Canvas, Sept. 18, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Oddly Matched", Sept. 25, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "The Blind Artist", Oct. 2, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Visionary Architecture", Oct. 2, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "A Gallery Remembers", Oct. 9, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Abstract Premises", Oct. 9, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "American Finds", Oct. 16, 1960 (Box 2)
  - (Magazine section) "Search for Art's True Magic", Oct. 16, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Odd Forces of Modern Criticism", Oct, 23, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "You're Welcome, Come In", Oct. 30, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Newsweek, Oct. 31, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "What's Inside", Nov. 6, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Artists and Materials", Nov. 20, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Art, Duty, and Pleasure, Nov. 27, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "The Victim of Velasquez", Nov. 28, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Nostalgia and the Forward Look", Dec. 4, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Third Dimension", Dec. 11, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "Barnes: Open at Last", Dec. 18, 1960 (Box 3)
  - "Memory Lane", Dec. 18, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Conant, Howard, Jan. 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Arrived Safely", Jan. 8, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Arts of Thailand", Jan. 15, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Corcoran Awards", Jan. 15, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Is Less More, and When for Whom, Jan. 22, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "It Didn't Work", Jan. 29, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "The Telephone Mystery", Feb. 5, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Modern Classes at Guggenheim", Feb. 7, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "For the Record", Feb. 12, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Vote of Confidence", Feb. 19, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Calder and Miro", Feb. 26, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Loplop the Waterwitch", Mar. 5, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Italian Drawings", Mar. 5, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Violence, Mystery, Evocation", Mar. 12, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "The Splendid Century", Mar. 12, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Sculpture Alive", Mar. 19, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Whither Art?", Mar. 26, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Art and the Fire Department", Apr. 2, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Art Critic Finds Hint of Sanity in Auto Design", Apr. 2, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Sculptures Spin in Recital Art Museum", Apr. 6, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Letter on a Dilemma", Apr. 30, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "A Private Road", May 7, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Or Not to Be"', June 11, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Trial by Drawing", June 18, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Hammock Reading", June 25, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Instruments as Art", June 25, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Delicious Innovator", July 2, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Provincetown Up", July 9, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "True Story, Happy Ending", July 23, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "West Coast Note", July 27, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "The World's Fair", July 30, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Transubstantiation at the Prado", July 30, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Artist Tenants Association", July 31, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "15 Polish Painters", Aug. 1, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Monster in Small Format", Aug. 6, 1961 (Box 3)
  - (Magazine section) "Who's Who and Why of Collectors", Aug. 6, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Book Review, Painting in 20th Century, Aug. 6, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Rembrandt, Plus", Aug. 13, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Monster in Small Format", Aug. 20, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Ointment Plus Fly", Aug. 27, 1961 (Box 3)
  - (Magazine Section) "Lessons of the Very Young Masters", Aug. 27, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Buy Prints, Buy American", Sept. 3, 1961 (Box 3)
  - "Big Show, Even Bigger Question", Sept. 10, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Feat or Folly", Sept. 17, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Sequeiros", Sept. 24, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Bernard Rader, Oct. 1, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "A Mixed-Up Show", Oct. 8, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "American Nudes", Oct. 15, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Mike Wallace Show", Oct. 20, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Magritte-Courbet", Oct. 22, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "International Exhibition Open in Pittsburgh", Oct. 27, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "This Way, Please", Oct. 29, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "A Very Painful Truth", Nov. 5, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Tragic World of Kaethe Kollwitz", Nov. 5, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Julius Bissier", Nov. 12, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "The Whitney Turns 30", Nov. 15, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "A Banner Year, Of Sorts", Nov. 26, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Red Stars and Bread", Dec. 3, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Art and the Artist, and the Bookmaker, Too", Dec. 3, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Street of Strugglers", Dec. 4, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Address: North Pole", Dec. 10, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Art of Grandma Moses", Dec. 14, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Whitney Again", Dec. 17, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "An Art Almanac", Dec. 24, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Delights at the Frick", Dec. 31, 1961 (Box 4)
  - "Sculpture Coming Up", Jan. 1, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Philadelphia American", Jan. 14, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Whole Men and Fragments", Jan. 21, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Art, History, Commerce", Jan. 28, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Soviet Children and Art", Feb. 4, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "An Impossible Exhibition", Feb. 11, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Letter From the Editor", Feb. 11, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Jean Dubuffet", Feb. 25, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Fernand Layer", Mar. 4, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Book Review, Painter of Record, Mar. 4, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Marsden Hartley", Mar. 11, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Prints in Brooklyn", Mar. 11, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Two Round Trips", Mar. 18, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Moore and Calder", Mar. 25, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "When You Call Me Good, Smile", Mar. 25, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "The Mysterious Visitors", Apr. 1, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Change of Pace", Apr. 8, 1962 (Box 4)
  - "Pride of Drawings", Apr. 15, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Letters, Daily Paper Article, Apr. 18, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Master Building", Apr. 22, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Seattle Art Show", Apr. 29, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Picasso Editorial", May 1, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Bay Area Report", May 6, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Leonard Baskin", May 13, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Sculpture Lesson", May 20, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Welcome Wind-Up", May 27, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Amy Crush", June, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Nation's Future TV", June, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Art in a Democracy", June 3, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Camera Vs. Painter", June 10, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Provincetown Report", June 17, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Some Pending Research", June 24, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Hogarth and 1962", July 1, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Shopper's Progress", July 8, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Bouquet for Mike Belmont", July 15, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Obscure But Exemplary", July 22, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Forty Americans", Ju1y 29, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Big Museum Question", Aug. 5, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "University Amateurs", Aug. 12, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Museum Directors", Aug. 17, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "An Open Letter to X", Aug. 19, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Arthur B. Daires and Modern Prints", Sept. 23, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Special Problem", Sept. 30, 1962 (Box 5)
  - (Magazine section) "Sculpture", Sept. 30, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "A Happy Week", Oct. 7, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Art in Colleges", Oct 14, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "In Minneapolis", Oct. 21, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Visitors from the West", Oct. 28, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Kline and Wyeth", Nov. 4, 1962 (Box 5)
  - "Armory Show, or, Whatever Became of Avant-Garde?", Apr. 7, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Temple In Extremes", Apr. 14, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Douanier (Rousseau) the Magic Man", Apr. 21, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Two Ways to Do It: DeKooning and Anderson", Apr. 28, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Rodin", May, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Rodin as a Silver Cord", May 5, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Manhattan is an Island", May 12, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Goodbye Forever", May 19, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Americans 1963", May 22, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Americans Once More", May 26, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Handy Little Hot Weather Manual for Prospective Art Critics", July 21, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Fly on the Wall", Aug. 18, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Larry Rivers", Aug. 21, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Liturgical Art", Aug. 25, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "And So To Labor Day", Sept. 1, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Braque", Sept. 1, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "A Public Sight", Sept. 8, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Biennale de Paris", Oct. 12, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Irish Painters", Oct. 13, 1965 (Box 5)
  - "Concentrated Delights", Oct. 20, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Stella Vs. Stella", Oct. 27, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Milton Avery", Nov. 3, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Crowded We", Nov. 10, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Nagare", Nov. 11, 1963 (Box 5)
  - "Maecenas and Midas", Nov. 17, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Matthew Head Letter to Editor, Nov. 20, 1963 (Box 6)
  - Soviet Article, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Leon Glub", Nov. 24, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Hedda Sterne", Dec. 1, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Small Packages", Dec. 8, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Whitney Annual", Dec. 15, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Toys by Artists", Dec. 22, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "Dear Reader", Dec. 29, 1963 (Box 6)
  - "A Wee Plug for a Worthy Cause", Jan. 5, 1964 (Box 6)
  - (Magazine section) "Russian Art", Jan. 5, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Girlie Show", Jan. 7, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Hello, Goodbye", Jan. 12, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Jackson-Pollack", Jan. 19 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Razzle-Dazzle", Jan. 26, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Hop, Skip, Jump", Feb. 2, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "African Weaponry", Feb. 5, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Baskin and the Sooty God", Feb. 9, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "American Via Maine", Feb. 16, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Gaston Lachise", Feb. 23, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Keane", Feb. 27, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Re Conscience", Mar. 1, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Painter's Eye", Mar. 8, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Philadelphian (Watkins)", Mar. 15, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Capital Salesroom", Mar. 16, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Tchelitchen", Mar. 22, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Oh Dada, Poor Dada", Mar. 28, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Pardon the Heresy", Mar. 29 1964 (Box 6)
  - "The Mitch Master- Van Gogh", Apr. 5, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Claes Oldenburg", Apr. 12, 1364 (Box 6)
  - "Maybe Hopeful", Apr. 12, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Sincerely Yours", Apr. 14, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Pieta", Apr. 20, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Art of World's Fair", Apr. 25, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Pre-Raphaelites", Apr. 26, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Spanish Pavilion", Apr. 28, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "The Fair as Art", May 3, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Ray of Light", May 10, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Oh Fly With Me", May 19, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Negroes in Art", May 24, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "My Fair Lady", May 25, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "MOMA", May 26, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "No Place Like It", May 31, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Pop Art", May 31, 1964 (Magazine section) (Box 6)
  - "Maxfield Parrish, Target Artist", June 7, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Add Fair Art", June 14, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Mort Sahl", June 19, 1964 (Box 6)
  - "Notes on Daubigny", June 21, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Notes on Daubigny", June 21, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "This Way (and That) to the American Art Shows", June 28, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Van Gogh Again, and Better", July 5, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Far, Far Out On Broadway", July 12, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Side Report", July 19, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "The Pieta and One Avalokiteshvan", July 26, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Drawings", July 26, 1964 (Magazine section) (Box 7)
  - "Horizontal Monologue", Aug. 2, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Auspicious Debut", Sept. 27, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Edward Hopper", Oct. 4, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "Straw Without Brick", Nov. 15, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "The Lounge-TV", Nov. 18, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "The Case of the'200,000 Weekend Guests", Dec. 6, 1964 (Box 7)
  - "ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ-1234567890" 1965, Dec. 27, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Jan. 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Thanking You In Advance", Jan. 3, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Come Back Michelangelo", Jan. 31, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Responsive Eye", Feb. 28, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Sometimes You Feel Sorry", Mar. 2, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "That's Right, It's Wrong", Mar. 14, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "A Gentle Revelation", Mar. 28, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Sorry, Can't Help You at All", May 30, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "1920's Revisited", July 4, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Trouble, Trouble. Trouble", July 11, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Our National Pride", July 31, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Aug. 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Sad Dream World of Gordon G.", Aug. 1, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Carousel", Aug. 11, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Overboard Comments About Cartoons", Aug. 22, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Catlin Show", Aug. 30, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Butler Show", Sept. 5, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Trozco Show", Sept. 12, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Robert Motherwell", Oct. 17, 1965 (Box 7)
  - "Why Artists Paint", Nov. 14, 1965 (Box 8)
  - "Da Vinci", Dec. 5, 1965 (Box 8)
  - "Munch Exhibition", Dec. 7, 1965 (Box 8)
  - "Dali", Dec. 18, 1965 (Box 8)
  - "The Quiet Necromancer", Dec. 19, 1965 (Box 8)
  - "Durer Drawings", Dec. 23, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Jan. 1966 (Box 8)
  - "Postscript", Jan. 1966 (Box 8)
  - Today Show, Jan. 2, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Feb. 1966 (Box 8)
- Correspondence by subject
  - Auction Letters, Jan.-Feb. 1966; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - G-H (Box 8)
  - Invitations, talks, lectures, committees, juries (Box 8)
  - Metropolitan seminars & "Mainstreams" (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, answered A-P, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, answered R-Z, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, unanswered, 1965; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, answered, 1966; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, unanswered, 1966; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, unanswered, 1966; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentifiable, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous recent, unanswered (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous interesting letters (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, requests for advice, reviews, clarifications, jobs, favors etc. (Box 10)
  - O'Doherty, Brian (Box 10)
  - "Onions" (Box 10)
  - "Orchids", 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Russian assignment, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Tobey, Mark (Box 10)
- Manuscripts
  - Articles, Feb. 1966-Sept. 1966 (Box 11)
  - Reviews, untitled (Box 10)
- Oversize material
  - "Printed Present" (Oversize 1)
  - Sketch, "The Critic" by M. Ponce de Leon (Oversize 1)
  - Television interview, New Orleans, 2 boxes (Oversize 2, 3)